Alan Houston

Full Stack Web Developer

3900 Tamil St. Austin, TX 78749 512.993.6800 AlanHouston.dev AlanHouston5000@gmail.com

Gaining experience from a diverse background, I pride myself on my communication skills, multitasking, and organizational proficiency. I work well with my coworkers and enjoy solving complex problems collaboratively. I love learning and enjoy keeping myself and my peers focused, motivated, and in good spirits. Please check out my website AlanHouston.dev for my attempt at playful professionalism!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Vybe Software Austin, TX

WEB DEVELOPER, JUNE 2019 - PRESENT

- Ongoing maintenance, customer support, QA for Leia: Website Builder: heyleia.com, 300.000+ users
- Design/create 350+ front end section templates with strict, editor specific HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, UX/UI. Backend PHP, MySQL
- Currently redesigning Leia for Real Estate, currently building Leia for Political Campaigns
- Build Wordpress plugins and themes to integrate Leia products into the platform
- Optimize subscribing clients' on-page SEO
- Assume ancillary tasks due to small-scale startup, five person team

Grassroots Realty *Austin, TX*

REALTOR®, APRIL 2017 - PRESENT

DEN Property Group Austin, TX

REALTOR®, AUGUST 2013 - APRIL 2017

- Primary focus: Customer service with constant communication
- Generate leads & maintain client relationships
- High dollar contract management
- Property management

Habitat Camping Rentals Austin, TX

OWNER/OPERATOR, MAY 2014 - PRESENT

- Project management during large multiple night festivals, 20-100 customers, crew of 2-6
- Inventory management: purchasing, maintaining, and storing 100's of inventory items
- B2B marketing to local festivals and venue owners
- End of fiscal year tax preparation

Austin Coding Academy *Austin, TX*

- Communicate via phone/email with prospective students, guiding them through the decision to level up their career into the tech industry
- Admissions process: initial interview, admissions assignment, followup calls, acceptance, and onboarding

TUTOR (part-time), MAY 2019 - JUNE 2019

- Provide individual and small group tutoring to students
- Assist students in improving academic achievement by meeting with them on a regular basis to clarify learning objectives

Mohawk Austin, TX

VENUE MANAGER, DECEMBER 2008 - JULY 2015

- Manage flow & well-being of 1000+ customers, 35+ shift employees: bar, production, floor,
 & security
- Face of company: interface with day-of promoters, police department, fire marshall, health enforcement, TABC, etc
- Fast-paced, constantly changing environment, continually adapting
- High responsibility: cash & safe balances, key holding: first to arrive, last to leave, staff scheduling

SKILLS

JavaScript • jQuery • PHP • MySQL • HTML • CSS • Bootstrap • MariaDB • MongoDB Mongoose • Node.js • Express.js • React • WordPress • RESTful API • Git/GitHub • Linux Webpack • Websocket • Angular Conversational Spanish

EDUCATION

Austin Coding Academy - Full Stack Web Developer Program - AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2019

Texas State University - BBA, Finance AUGUST 2000 - DECEMBER 2004